Guide to the National Education Association Web Archives Collection, 2015-2018 NEA1013
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
National Education Association Web Archives Collection (Version 1)
Crawled 9 times between 2015 July 6 through November 28, 2018
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
National Education Association of the United States
NEA1013
19 item(s)
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Arrangement
Chose the appropriate language that matches the level you are describing:
For Collection: Organized into [number] series: [list series titles]
For Series or Subseries: If the series has subseries use the same format as the Collection note to state the titles of the subseries
Series: Arranged [alphabetically, chronologically, etc.]
Related Materials
The records of the National Education Association. The collection inventory can be found here: https://library.gwu.edu/scrc/search/finding-aids-by-topic/nea
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of snapshots taken from 20 websites operated by or affiliated with the National Education Association and archived. The websites were selected because they are affiliated with the NEA, either operated by the Association or on behalf of NEA leadership.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection was harvested and archived through Archive-It
Education policy; Education; Education -- Finance; Civil rights; Educational law and legislation; Employee rights; Education, Bilingual -- United States; Women's rights; Gay rights
- Education Votes, Harvested twelve times between Jul 6, 2015 - Nov 29, 2018; Series 15
- Healthy Futures, Harvested five times between July 6, 2015 - November 28, 2018; Series 17
  Scope and Contents
  This website is part of a strategy to improve the health of students, educators, and other members of the school community. Health is defined to include mental health, nutrition, environment, disease prevention, and crisis response.
- Healthy Futures, Crawled five times between April 11, 2017 and November 28, 2018; Series 10
- Legislative Action Center, Crawled five times between April 11, 2017 and November 28, 2018; Series 11
- Lily's Blackboard, Harvested 8 times between Jul 6, 2015 - Nov 29, 2018; Series 14
- My School, My Voice, Crawled seven times between October 25, 2017 and November 28, 2018
- NEA Academy, Harvested six times between July 6, 2015 - November 28, 2018; Series 13
- NEA Asian & Pacific Islander Caucus, Harvested three times between October 25, 2017 and November 28, 2018; Series 5; The website of the Asian & Pacific Islander Caucus. The website provides a short statement of purpose, a membership form, and links for activists.
- NEA Black Caucus, Crawled three times between October 25, 2017 and November 28, 2018; Series 3; The website of the NEA's Black Caucus. The Caucus was founded in 1971 to represent African-American staff working in a predominantly white institution. The website provides governance information about the Caucus, including identifying leadership and providing up-to-date bylaws and statements of mission and vision. The site also provides information about upcoming events and available scholarships.
- NEA Hispanic Caucus, Crawled three times between October 25, 2017, and November 28, 2018; Series 4; The website of the NEA's Hispanic Caucus. The website provides governing documents for the Caucus, including a statement of purpose and bylaws. There are also a listing of events held or created by the Caucus, links to resources for members, allies, and activists, and a list of allies.
- NEA Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender, Queer+ Caucus, Harvested three times between October 25, 2017 and November 28, 2018; Series 8
- NEA Main Website, Harvested seventeen times between Jul 6, 2015 - Nov 28, 2018; Series 12
- NEA Today, Harvested ten times between July 6, 2015 - November 28, 2018; Series 18
  NEA Today is the flagship NEA publication. This is the web version of a physical publication that can be found in the collection. The magazine provides information on issues of key significance to the Association, including education policy, educators' working conditions, pedagogy, and social issues. The articles are generally hyper-linked. Many of those links are to websites not operated by the NEA.
- NEA Women's Caucus, Crawled three times between October 25, 2017 and November 28, 2018; Series 7
- Priority Schools Campaign, Crawled five times between July 6, 2015 and November 28, 2018; Series 9
- Teacher Leadership Initiative, Harvested four times between July 6, 2015 - Nov 28, 2018; Series 16; The website of the NEA's Teacher Leadership Institute. The Institute's purpose is to recruit, prepare, activate, and support the next generation of teachers to lead a transformed teaching profession. The website provides statements of purpose, benchmarks for professional competencies for teachers, and testimonials from former students.
- Teacher Leadership Institute, Crawled three times between October 25, 2017, and November 28, 2018; Series 6; The website of the NEA's Teacher Leadership Institute. The Institute's purpose is to recruit, prepare, activate, and support the next generation of teachers to lead a transformed teaching profession. The website provides statements of purpose, benchmarks for professional competencies for teachers, and testimonials from former students.